Emily Greenley collection, 1983-2011
Emory University
Emily Greenley collection, 1983-2011
Corbett, William, 1942-
Manuscript Collection No. 1228
1 linear ft. (3 boxes)
Collection of materials collected by William Corbett about Emily Greenley during a project to edit a posthumous book of her poetry.
Emory University Manuscript, Archives, and Rare Book Library
Source
Gift, 2011.
Restrictions on Access
Special restrictions apply: The journal is restricted until January 1, 2032 for privacy considerations.
Researchers must contact MARBL in advance to access audio recordings in this collection.
Biographical Note
William Corbett (1942-), poet and professor. William Corbett has taught in the Expository Writing Program at Harvard University and is a director in the Writing and Humanistic Studies Program at Massachusetts Institute of Technology. He also is the editor of Pressed Wafer, a press specializing in poetry.
Emily Greenley (1968-1990), poet. Greenley was a student of William Corbett while at Harvard University. She published numerous poems in Harvard's student publications. After graduation, she lived in Boston, Massachusetts before committing suicide in 1990.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of materials collected by William Corbett about Emily Greenley during a project to edit a posthumous book of her poetry. Material includes a proof copy of that book of poetry (which was never published), correspondence related to the project, and source material collected from friends, family, and publications. Materials about Greenley include her journal, notebooks of her writings, and photographs taken by her. Rolf Noyer prepared an index of both the photographs and writings, which is included in the collection. All the Greenley materials in this collection are photocopies, with the exception of the photographs and issues of journals in which her poetry appeared. The collection also includes an audio recording and related flier for a poetry reading following Greenley's death.
Arrangement Note
Arranged by record type.
Selected Search Terms
Personal Names
Greenley, Emily, 1968-1990.
Topical Terms
Authors, American--20th century.; American poetry--20th century.; Women poets, American.
Form/Genre Terms
Poems.
Container List
- Emily Greenley
- Harvard Advocate, volume 119, number 1-2 (November-December 1985) [contains Emily Greenley poetry] (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Journal [photocopy] [RESTRICTED] (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Journal [photocopy] [RESTRICTED] (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Notebook [photocopy], 1983-1987 [1 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Notebook [photocopy], 1983-1987 [2 of 2] (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Poetry and prose, catalogue, compiled by Rolf Noyer, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Poetry and prose [photocopies], 1984-1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Photographs, catalogue, compiled by Rolf Noyer, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Photographs [identified], undated [1 of 3] (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Photographs [identified], undated [2 of 3] (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Photographs [identified], undated [3 of 3] (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Photographs [unidentified], undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- William Corbett
- Correspondence, 1990-2011 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Knowledge, unpublished collection of Emily Greenley poetry edited by William Corbett, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Lift #6, April 1991 [contains Emily Greenley poetry with an introduction by William Corbett] (Box 2, Folder 4)
- "Word of Mouth: the Poetry of Emily Greenley," poetry reading by William Corbett and others, flier, March 17, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- "Word of Mouth: the Poetry of Emily Greenley," poetry reading by William Corbett and others, audio recording, March 17, 1991 (Box -, Folder -)